{"tossups": [{"question": "Two characters by this author relive a game of To Hell and Gone that they had played in a rusted Chevy. One of those characters used his farm money to buy gentleman's clothes for a date with their pen pal, Ethel, and while rehearsing it, called his brother a (+) swartgat. In another play, a character by this author is told that he hits his partner, Hilda Samuels, too much. One character in that play is spit on after baring his ass to his boss's son, and his reading about scalars leads to a discussion about Tolstoy, Darwin, and Fleming as men of (*) magnitude. That character explains the ideal of ballroom dancing as free of collisions to the title character. For ten points, name this playwright who wrote of Morris and Zachariah in Blood Knot and of Sam and Willie in Master Harold...and the Boys.", "answer": "Athol Fugard", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Athol <b><u>Fugard</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Athol Fugard", "Fugard"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel imagines herself representing Britain in the Olympicsin the event of nettle-cutting. That character in this novel based her story TwoFigures by a Fountain upon watching her sister diving to recover a piece of a broken(+) vase, and she had earlier been unable to perform her play The Trials of Arabella. In response to a vulgar letter to her sister, that character falsely accused its author of the (*) rape of Lola, resulting in his joining the British Army during World War II. That man, Robbie Turner, is eventually reunited with his love Cecilia in the new life written for them. For ten points, name this novel about Briony Tallis's quest for absolution written by Ian McEwan.", "answer": "Atonement", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Atonement</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Atonement", "Atonement"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A friend of this work's protagonist named Shalini lost her short term memoryin a deck collapse. The protagonist of this work helps fake the death of Adam Rich.The protagonist's younger brother gets a full scholarship to Black Pine Center and isfrequently told that his hat smells like (+) urine. The protagonist appears on televisioninterviewing Judd the cartoonist, and earlier regrets a sticker he sees in a bathroom bar saying \"Screw those idiots (*) Might Magazine\". The protagonist's father dies suddenly from lung cancer, and a month later, after a protracted nosebleed, his mother dies of stomach cancer. The protagonist moves from Lake Forest, Illinois to Berkeley and takes guardianship of his orphaned younger brother Toph. For ten points, name this memoir by Dave Eggers.", "answer": "A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "A <b><u>Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius", "Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, the narrator is told about peasants who were upsetthat their masters bought them scythes since they did not get to banter with thesalesmen. In another story, the narrator meets Arina, who had been a housemaid forAlexandr Zvyerkoff, while visiting (+) Yermolai. In yet another work, the protagonistconfronts a Prince during a dancing game of La Confidente, leading to a duel in which he shot the Prince non-fatally in the head but the Prince refused to (*) finish him. That work ends with the Prince leaving Liza, who then ignores the advances of Tchulkaturin. One collection by this writer contains Hor and Kalinitch and sees the narrator meet Polutikin while hunting birds. For ten points, name this Russian author of Diary of a Superfluous Man and Sportsman's Sketches.", "answer": "Ivan Turgenev                                                                                                                                                                                                                ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ivan Turgenev</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ivan Turgenev", "Ivan Turgenev"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man worked with Adam Real-Last-Name-Unknown. This writer described aformative experience watching a cook have sex with a bride at her wedding receptionat a restaurant in Provincetown. This writer described how working for an \"Italianfraternal organization\" inspired his novel (+) Bone in the Throat. He lost a job aftermishearing an interview question, answering \"Next to nothing\" to the question \"What do you know about meat?\" This man noted a turning point in his life when he ate raw (*) oysters with Monsieur Saint-Jour in France as a child, and he called a halved fish head the best meal of his life, which he ate while working in Tokyo for his restaurant Les Halles. For ten points, name this author of Kitchen Confidential, a chef whose later book inspired a television show, No Reservations.", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Anthony Bourdain</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Anthony Bourdain", "Anthony Bourdain"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel indicates another's demise by drawing a \"G\" in theair with her finger. The ship La Paloma catches fire shortly after it arrives from HongKong. In this novel, a character referred to as \"the fat man\" tells of a tribute paid bythe (+) Knights Hospitallers to Charles V. The protagonist is pursued by his partner'srecent widow, Iva, and is questioned by Lieutenant Dundy and Tom Polhaus. (*)Miles Archer and Floyd Thursby are shot after the protagonist is hired by a girl with pseudonym Wonderly named Brigid O'Shaughnessy. The protagonist is later commissioned by Joel Cairo to find the title object, which turns about to be a forgery from the Russian Kemidov. For ten points, name this novel in which Sam Spade investigates a bird statuette, written by Dashiell Hammett.", "answer": "The Maltese Falcon", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Maltese Falcon</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Maltese Falcon", "Maltese Falcon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this work, a gossip tells of Paca la Roseta, whose husband was tied up sothat she could be abducted to the olive grove. This play's third act starts with anotherwise silent meal interrupted by a mating horse thudding against the wall. Onecharacter is angry to be given a red-and-green flowered (+) fan instead of a black one,and she later tells her daughter \"May God strike you dead, you two-faced scorpion!\" for stealing a sister's picture. One character claims that a (*) suitor left her window at 1 in the morning, although Amelia and Poncia attest he left at 4; that man, Pepe el Romano, was engaged to Angustias and loved by the younger sister Adela, who ultimately hangs herself. For ten points, name this play about the daughters of the domineering title mother written by Federico Garcia Lorca.", "answer": "The House of Bernarda Alba (or La Casa de Bernarda Alba)                                                                                                                                                                                                                              ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>House of Bernarda Alba</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The House of Bernarda Alba", "House of Bernarda Alba"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or La Casa de Bernarda Alba"}, {"question": "This country's government of national salvation declared that \"salvation liesin retreat\". After skirmishes with the national guard, hotels in this country wereoccupied by the poor following the collapse of the tourism industry. Three men werefound in this country's capital by a woman carrying an (+) elm branch, and earliertwo of those men had left this country when border guards were distracted by a flock of starlings. This home country of Joachim Sassa and Jose Anai \u0327co saw the deaths of thirty thousand people in an (*) earthquake, including the drowning death of Jacques the Anabaptist in its harbor, leading to the auto-da-fes in Candide. For ten points, name this country which, in Jos \u0301e Saramago's The Stone Raft, separated from Europe with its neighbor, Spain.", "answer": "Portugal (or The Portuguese Republic)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Portugal</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Portugal", "Portugal"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or The Portuguese Republic"}, {"question": "In this story, anthropology professor William Channing Webb had studied theEsquimaux in Greenland and was later questioned by John Raymond Legrasse, whohad led a raid on a voodoo meeting outside (+) New Orleans. The crew of a Norwegianship is rescued by the Australian Vigilant with only its captain Johansen surviving and opens a (*) portal on an uncharted island in the Indian ocean. The narrator of this story is the executor of the estate of his great-uncle George Gammell Angell, in which role he finds a bas-relief of a monster he described as a cross between a human, a dragon, and an octopus. The title character of this story is said to wait dreaming in his house at R'lyeh. For ten points, name this short story describing the cults of a water deity written by H.P. Lovecraft.", "answer": "The Call of Cthulhu", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Call of Cthulhu</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Call of Cthulhu", "Call of Cthulhu"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this story is motivated by the inefficiency of the term \"thirty-three Uruguayans\" to develop new words for the numbers up to twenty-four thousand.That character is said to understand the \"tempestuous mane of a stallion\" as thenarrator understands a circle or triangle. (+) After receiving a letter telling of hisfather's illness, the narrator visits the title character to retrieve his copies of Pliny's Historia Naturalis and Quicherat's Gradus at Parnassum. The title character was called (*) \"chronometer\" because during the narrator's first encounter with him on a footpath, the former knew it was ten minutes to eight. For ten points, name this short story about a resident of Fray Bentos who, after falling from a horse, develops total recall, written by Jorge Luis Borges.", "answer": "Funes, the Memorious (or Funes, el memorioso)                                                                                                                                                                                                                              ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Funes, the Memorious</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Funes, the Memorious", "Funes, the Memorious"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Funes, el memorioso"}, {"question": "One character in this play wrote his will on a roll of toilet paper after beinglocked in a toilet overnight. Another character says that man could not kill himselfbecause he wears a seatbelt at a drive-in movie. One character comes home late fromwork, causing the other's (+) London broil to dry out right before their double datewith Gwendolyn and Cecily. One character is four weeks late with his alimony to Blanche, while the other is suicidal after (*) separating from his wife, Frances. The character Speed leaves when a Pure-A-Tron air cleaner disrupts a poker game, which in the first act had served \"brown\" and \"green\" sandwiches. At the end, the Pigeon sisters allow Felix to move in with them and out of sports writer Oscar Madison's apartment. For ten points, name this Neil Simon play about two unlikely roommates.", "answer": "The Odd Couple", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Odd Couple</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Odd Couple", "Odd Couple"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this work, Father Leblanc discusses justice by telling the story of a girl put todeath for stealing a pearl necklace, only later for it to be revealed that a magpie didit. One character in this work notes that English ships have been anchored for fourdays at the mouth of the (+) Gaspereau. Another character finds her father-in-law,Basil the blacksmith, while rafting on the Atchafalaya River, after which she travels with a Shawnee guide to the (*) Ozarks looking for her lost husband. This poem's first half ends with the burning of the village of Grand Pr \u0301e and the expulsion of its people. While working in an almshouse in Pennsylvania, the title character finally finds Gabriel Lajeunesse. For ten points, name this epic poem about an Acadian girl written by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.", "answer": "Evangeline: A Tale of Acadie", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Evangeline: A Tale of Acadie</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Evangeline: A Tale of Acadie", "Evangeline: A Tale of Acadie"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This play ends with its matriarch declaring \"No man at all can be living for ever,and we must be satisfied.\" A woman in this play infers the demise of her brother whenher mother returns carrying a piece of bread wrapped in cloth. Another characteridentifies a sock she had sewn by counting its stitches after a young (+) priest broughta bundle of clothes that she was to hide from her mother. The sisters Nora and Cathleen discuss how it would take seven days to get to (*) Donegal from their island of Inishmaan. Sheamus, Shawn, and Patch carry in a body covered by a bit of sail; that man, Bartley, had gone searching for his missing brother Michael when he was knocked into the ocean by the gray pony. For ten points, name this play about the many drowned sons of Maurya written by John Millington Synge.", "answer": "Riders to the Sea", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Riders to the Sea</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Riders to the Sea", "Riders to the Sea"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story, a member of this profession assists with a stranger's christeningin Yvetot. While awaiting the arrival of members of this profession, a captain isentertained by setting off a makeshift mine made of a stolen china teapot. One ofthese characters uses a basket with two whole (+) fowls to feed her starving travelcompanions on the way to Dieppe. Le Devoir travels to Rouen to fetch a group of these characters, including Eva \"the Tomato\" and a Jewess named (*) Rachel. One of these characters becomes incensed at a dinner when her date insults women and the French, while another named Elizabeth Rousset is held in Totes by a foreign officer. A member of this profession stabs Mademoiselle Fifi to death. For ten points, name this type of character exemplified by Guy de Maupassant's Boule de Suif.", "answer": "prostitutes (accept equivalents)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>prostitutes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["prostitutes", "prostitutes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept equivalents"}, {"question": "This author chooses a lock of his father's hair and a portrait of his sister \"If I apleasant keepsake\" had to take to the afterlife. This man likens his country to a widowholding a bloody carnation in a poem that calls the night one of his two homelands.He declares (+) \"It is my verse you have seen\" \"If you've seen a mount of sea foam\"in a poem that continues \"My verse is a gentle green/ and also a flaming red\". This writer says he will give a white rose to his friend as well as his enemy in a poem beginning (*) \"I have a white rose to tend/ In July as in January\". The opening poem of his most famous collection begins \"A sincere man am I/ from the land where palm trees grow.\" For ten points, name this poet whose Versos Sencillos are the basis of Guantanamera, the national song of his native Cuba.", "answer": "J \u0301ose Mart \u0301\u0131", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>J \u0301ose Mart \u0301\u0131</u></b>", "acceptable": ["J \u0301ose Mart \u0301\u0131", "J \u0301ose Mart \u0301\u0131"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One work in this collection uses the example of a fisherman sailing into the fogbefore summarizing \"We cannot think of a time that is oceanless\". Another poemin this collection uses an antiquated spelling of the word \"dancing\" in a discussionof marriage, and the narrator claims to have wasted twenty years of \"l'entre deuxguerres\". The final poem claims that the (+) \"only hope\" is \"To be redeemed fromfire by fire\". The third work in this collection compares a river to a \"strong brown god\" and notes \"Time is no healer: the patient is no longer here\". Its second poem concludes (*) \"In my end is my beginning\", while the first begins \"Time present and time past/ are perhaps both present in time future\". For ten points, name this collection consisting of East Coker, The Dry Salvages, Little Gidding, and Burnt Norton written by T.S. Eliot", "answer": "Four Quartets", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Four Quartets</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Four Quartets", "Four Quartets"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel thinks that \"take a leak\" means \"steal a mirror\" andwas abducted by the Pluto Gang. In this novel, the Sacred Miracle Cave was damagedby a flood of industrial runoff from Barrytron. One character comes up with the story(+) Gilgongo! while hitchhiking to the Midland City arts festival, and his novel Now It Can Be Told convinces the protagonist that he is the only creature in the universe with free will. The text of this novel is interspersed with drawings including female underpants and an asshole. This novel ends with the protagonist attacking (*) Wayne Hoobler and his secretary Francine Pefko and biting off the finger of Kilgore Trout. For ten points, name this novel about the car dealer Dwayne Hoover by Kurt Vonnegut whose name refers to martinis.", "answer": "Breakfast of Champions: or Goodbye, Blue Monday!", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Breakfast of Champions: or Goodbye, Blue Monday!</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Breakfast of Champions: or Goodbye, Blue Monday!", "Breakfast of Champions: or Goodbye, Blue Monday!"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of these characters is only seen crying \"piteously\" at being unable to assista woman with an infant. Another of these characters finds two children hanging onhis feet he calls Ignorance and Want before departing. That character had appearedwearing an open green robe surrounded by food. A later one leads a visit to see (+)Joe and Mrs. Dilber dividing a plunder including bed curtains and exits by turning into a bedpost. Those characters were preceded by another who first appeared in a (*) door knocker, was recognized by his pigtail, and dragged chains. One of these characters visits Fezziwig's party while another is named Jacob Marley. For ten points, name this type of character, three of which visited Scrooge in Dickens's A Christmas Carol representing Christmases past, present, and future.", "answer": "ghosts in A Christmas Carol                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ghosts in A Christmas Carol</u></b>", "acceptable": ["ghosts in A Christmas Carol", "ghosts in A Christmas Carol"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Dr. Dunster tells the title character of one of this author's short stories that herupsighted friend Peggy Bond has cataracts, and he agrees to visit her in Byfleet. Thatwoman sews a button for a passing trainman in order to earn a trip to the Centennialcelebration in Philadelphia. The protagonist of another of this author's short storiesreceives a (+) jackknife on the first day of an unsuccessful hunt with a man she metwhile retrieving the wandering cow Mistress Moolly for Mrs. Tilley. This author of (*)The Flight of Betsey Lane told of a girl named Sylvia waking up at dawn to climb a tree in order to earn ten dollars from a visiting ornithologist, but deciding not to tell that man the whereabouts of the bird he seeks for his collection. For ten points, name this author of A White Heron.", "answer": "Sarah Orne Jewett", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Sarah Orne <b><u>Jewett</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sarah Orne Jewett", "Jewett"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this novel is visited by a man who speaks with no spaces betweenhis words and is the subject of the book's only illustration. The protagonist's cat isthe only character in this novel with a proper name, as a chauffeur names it Kipper.The protagonist checks into the (+) Dolphin Hotel with his girlfriend, whose ears hebelieves have a special power, while looking for a character pictured on his lighter. The action of this novel begins when the (*) Boss takes exception to a landscape photo used to advertise a life insurance company. The protagonist uses a grandfather clock to blow up a house in the mountains at the insistence of his business partner, the Rat. For ten points, name this novel in which the unnamed protagonist searches for the title star-backed animal written by Haruki Murakami.", "answer": "A Wild Sheep Chase (or Hitsuji o meguru b \u0304oken)                                                                                                                                                                         ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "A <b><u>Wild Sheep Chase</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Wild Sheep Chase", "Wild Sheep Chase"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Hitsuji o meguru b \u0304oken"}], "bonuses": []}